Babbitt, Bill; Collection apap204
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bill Babbitt Collection
1967-2016
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap204
4.82 cubic ft.
The Bill Babbitt Collection documents nearly ten years of legal efforts to spare his brother Manny Babbitt's life from execution, and two decades of advocacy activities to try to abolish the death penalty.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department Special Collections and Archives by Bill Babbitt in 2008, 2014, and 2016. Mike Camoin donated audio and video materials in 2017 and 2019.
Biographical Sketch
Bill Babbitt is an activist in the abolition movement. He regularly speaks out against the capital punishment system after promising his younger brother Manny he would campaign to end the death penalty. On May 4, 1999 Bill Babbitt witnessed fifty-year-old Manny Babbitt's execution by the State of California at San Quentin prison.
The sons of an émigré from the Cape Verde Islands off the coast of western Africa, Manny and Bill Babbitt grew up in a family of eight children in Wareham, Massachusetts. Enlisting in the Marines as a teenager, Manny Babbitt served two tours of duty in Vietnam, including fighting at the siege at Khe Sanh in 1968. He later received a Purple Heart for wounds sustained during his military service in 1998, while a prisoner on Death Row.
In the years following his discharge Manny Babbitt lived in Massachusetts and Rhode Island where he suffered from schizophrenia and post-traumatic stress disorder. According to Carbone, he spent time in psychiatric institutions, failed at relationships, lived periodically on the streets, drank and engaged in drug use, and went to prison for committing increasingly violent crimes. He moved in September 1980 to Sacramento, California to be with his brother Bill and sister-in-law Linda. There Manny Babbitt was ultimately tried and convicted of the murder of an elderly woman, Leah Schendel, who died of cardiac arrest after being severely beaten during a robbery in her home in December 1980.
After discovering his brother might be involved in this crime, Bill Babbitt approached the police and assisted them with the arrest of Manny Babbitt. Bill Babbitt states the authorities promised his brother would receive psychological help and placement in a mental health facility rather than on Death Row. In 1982, however, after being found sane and guilty of murder, Manny Babbitt was sentenced to death. According to Doyle, his family strongly believes that his initial lawyers were not competent nor did they offer post-traumatic stress disorder as part of the defense. While Manny Babbitt never denied committing the crime, he stated he could not remember anything about that night.
During the 1990s Manny Babbitt had a new legal defense team dedicated to trying to appeal his conviction, secure a new trial, and spare his life through legal channels. It was led by public defender and lead counsel Jessica McGuire and a fellow Vietnam veteran and trial attorney Chuck Patterson. In addition to Manny and Bill Babbitt's family and supporters, other Vietnam veterans also petitioned California Governor Gray Davis for clemency in this case. Both legal activity and media coverage of the case intensified in the early months of 1999, leading up to Governor Davis denying clemency, several high courts rejecting last minute appeals and intervention, and Manny Babbitt's subsequent execution.
Bill Babbitt continues to campaign against the death penalty and is frequently interviewed on network television news programs, radio stations, major daily newspapers, and magazines. He attends anti-death penalty rallies, testifies before state legislative committees, and often speaks alongside David Kaczynski, the executive director of New Yorkers Against the Death Penalty, before student and legal groups. David Kaczynski assisted federal authorities with the apprehension of his brother Ted Kaczynski, known as the "Unabomber." The documentaries And Then One Night: The Making of Dead Man Walking with Sister Helen Prejean and Mike Farrell and A Question of Justice, also with David Kaczynski, share the story of Bill and Manny Babbitt.
Bill Babbitt is active in several national organizations that oppose capital punishment. He was a board member of Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation from 2000-2004 and is a founding board member of Murder Victims' Families for Human Rights, where he still serves today.
Scope and Contents
The Bill Babbitt Collection documents nearly ten years of legal efforts to spare his borther Manny Babbitt's life from execution, and two decades of advocacy activities to try to abolish the death penalty. The bulk of materials are court records from the 1990s related to Manny Babbitt's case. In addition, the collection includes the contents of Manny Babbitt's cell at San Quentin at the time of his execution, correspondence from both Manny and Bill Babbitt, speeches, prison records, materials from death penalty abolitionist organizations and conferences, and news coverage about the case and Bill Babbitt's ongoing advocacy work.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Legal Materials, 1991-1999
Series 2 - Manny Babbitt, 1970-1999, Undated
Series 3 - Advocacy, 1995-2008, Undated
This series includes documents related to Bill Babbitt's campaign to end the death penalty. Correspondence, speeches, documents from the organizations Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation and Murder Victims' Families for Human Rights, pamphlets from various conferences, background information and data on capital punishment, and a printed tribute to Manny Babbitt comprise this series. There also are numerous news articles about Manny and Bill Babbitt spanning the years 1998 through 2008.
Separated Materials
Archivists transferred the following titles: Brothers: 26 Stories of Love and Rivlary by Andrew Blauner; Buffalo Soldier by Ollen Hunt; Coffee Shop God by Therese Bartholomew; The Death Penalty in the United States, a Polymorphous Torture by Arnaud Gaillard; Detour to Death Row by David Atwood; Dignity Denied: The Experience of Murder Victims' Families Who Oppose the Death Penalty by Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation; The Forgotten Hero of My Lai by Trent Angers; Henry Hyde's Moral Universe by Dennis Bernstein and Leslie Kean; Journey of Hope...From Violence to Healing by Bill Pelke; Just Call Me Mike by Mike Farrell; Killing Time: An Investigation Into the Death Row Case of Mumia Abu-Jamal by Dave Lindorff; Kolmastoista Askel by Caroline Koivisto; The Last Place I Looked by Herbert D. Blake;Lessons from Grand Bay by Peter K.B. St. Jean; Report: Third World Congress Against the Death Penalty; The Petrified Heart by Charles E. Patterson; The Ride by Brian Macquarrie; Det Trettonde Steget by Caroline Koivisto to the book division of Special Collections.
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Capital punishment--United States; California Supreme Court; Babbitt, Manny; Sacramento County (Calif.); Legal documents; Aerogrammes; Administrative records; Newsletters
- Legal Materials, 1991-1999; 1; 1.82 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The majority of this series consists of court records from Manny Babbitt's case. There are materials from the District Court for the Eastern District of California, Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, California Supreme Court, and U.S. Supreme Court. The series also contains other legal documents, such as Manny Babbitt's last will and testament, and legal correspondence.
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1991 August-November (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - Legal Correspondence, 1991; 1993-1994; 1997-1999 (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - California Supreme Court, Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus, 1992 November (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court- Reply to Informal Response, 1993 June (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1995 August (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 January (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 February-March (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 8)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 April (Box 1 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 9)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Request to Expand. Exhibits: Vol. I (1 of 2), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Request to Expand. Exhibits: Vol. I (2 of 2), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Exhibits: Vol. II (1 of 3), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Exhibits: Vol. II (2 of 3), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Exhibits: Vol. II (3 of 3), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Exhibits: Vol. III (1 of 2), 1996 May (Box 2 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California Exhibits: Vol. III (2 of 2), 1996 May (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 June (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 August (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1996 August-December (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - District Court, 1997 February-March (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - District Court: Vol. I of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings (1 of 3), 1997 March (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - District Court: Vol. I of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings (2 of 3), 1997 March (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
  - District Court: Vol. I of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings (3 of 3), 1997 March (Box 3 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 8)
  - District Court: Vol. II of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings (1 of 2), 1997 March (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - District Court: Vol. II of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings (2 of 2), 1997 March (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - District Court: Vol. III of Appendix to Motion to Amend Findings, 1997 March (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1997 May (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - Court of Appeals for the 9th Circuit, 1997-1998 (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - Court of Appeals for the 9th Circuit- Source Material (1 of 2), ca. 1997 (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - Court of Appeals for the 9th Circuit- Source Material (2 of 2), ca. 1997 (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
  - District Court for the Eastern District of California, 1998 July (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 8)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals for the 9th Circuit, 1998 October-1999 February (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 9)
  - U.S. Supreme Court- Petition for Writ of Certiorari, 1998 December (Box 4 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 10)
  - U.S. Supreme Court, 1999 January-February (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - Superior Court of California, County of Sacramento, 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - Choice of Execution Method Form, 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - Incomplete Petition for Clemency, 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - Supreme Court: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. I (1 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - Supreme Court: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. I (2 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - Supreme Court: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. I (3 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
  - Supreme Count: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. II (1 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 8)
  - Supreme Count: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. II (2 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 9)
  - Supreme Count: Exhibits to Petition for Clemency. Vol. II (3 of 3), 1999 March (Box 5 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 10)
  - Reply to Response to Clemency Petition, 1999 April (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 1)
  - Last Will and Testament, 1999 April (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 2)
  - California Supreme Court, Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus and Emergency Application for Stay of Execution, 1999 April (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 3)
  - California Supreme Court, Exhibits to Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus and Emergency Application for Stay of Execution (1 of 2), 1999 April (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 4)
  - California Supreme Court, Exhibits to Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus and Emergency Application for Stay of Execution (2 of 2), 1999 April (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 5)
  - Death Certificate, 1999 May (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 6)
  - Babbitt Witness List, Undated (Box 6 (1-Legal Materials), Folder 7)
- Manny Babbitt, 1967-1999; Undated; 2; 1.83 cubic ft.
  The series consists of the contents of Manny Babbitt's cell at the time of his execution in May 1999, materials relating to his time in San Quentin, and documents about his Marine Corps service. This series contains Manny Babbitt's original works, including several poems. There also is an empty cardboard box which housed Manny Babbitt's personal items in his cell. Please note that the dates for the series are not inclusive and the bulk of files date from the 1990s.
  - U.S. Marine Corps Private First Class Promotion, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 1)
  - Discharge Report, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 2)
  - Publications, 1982; 1993; 1998-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 3)
  - Legal Correspondence, 1990-1992; 1995-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence (1 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence (2 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence (3 of 3), 1990-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 7)
  - The Battle of Khe Sanh, 1991 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 8)
  - Khe Sanh Veterans Reunion, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 9)
  - Visitor Approval Forms, 1993; 1999; Undated (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 10)
  - Ramadan Readings, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from State of California or San Quentin, 1996-1999; Undated (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 12)
  - Manny Babbitt, San Quentin Personal Funds, 1997-1999 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 13)
  - Copy of Purple Heart Award Certificate, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 14)
  - Book excerpts, Poems and Drawings, 1998; Undated (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 1)
  - Inmate Work Supervisors Time Log, 1998-1999 (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 2)
  - Vietnam Veterans Group, 1998-1999 (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 3)
  - Petition for Clemency, 1999 March (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 4)
  - Exhibits to Petition for Clemency Vol. II (1 of 3), 1999 March (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 5)
  - Exhibits to Petition for Clemency Vol. II (2 of 3), 1999 March (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 6)
  - Exhibits to Petition for Clemency Vol. II (3 of 3), 1999 March (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 7)
  - Clemency Decision, 1999 April (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 8)
  - Reply to Response to Clemency Petition, 1999 April (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 9)
  - Property Inventory, 1999 May 4 (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 10)
  - The Heart of Understanding, Undated (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 11)
  - Khe Sanh Citation, Undated (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 12)
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 13)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 3 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 1)
  - Stamps, Undated (Box 3 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 2)
  - Valley of Decision, 1991 (Box 3 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 3)
  - Empty cardboard box which housed Manny Babbitt's personal items in his cell at San Quentin, Undated (Box 4 (2-Manny Babbitt), Folder 1)
- Advocacy, 1982-2016; Undated; 3; 1.17 cubic ft.
  This series includes documents related to Bill Babbitt's campaign to end the death penalty and media coverage about Manny Babbitt's case. Correspondence, speeches, documents from the organizations Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation and Murder Victims' Families for Human Rights, pamphlets from various conferences, records of Bill's travels to advocate against capital punishment, background information and data on capital punishment, and a printed tribute to Manny Babbitt comprise this series. There also is substantials news coverage about Manny and Bill Babbitt in print, audio, and video formats.
  - Manny Babbitt Articles, 1982 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 1)
  - Advocacy Newsletters (1 of 2), 1990-2011; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 2)
  - Advocacy Newsletters (2 of 2), 1990-2011; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 3)
  - Conferences and Events, 1994; 1999-2006 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 4)
  - Bill and Linda Babbitt Correspondence (1 of 2), 1995; 1999-2006 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 5)
  - Bill and Linda Babbitt Correspondence (2 of 2), 1995; 1999-2006 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 6)
  - Death Penalty Facts, 1995; 2000; 2005; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 7)
  - Speeches and Articles, 1996; 2001; 2006; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 8)
  - Book Tributes, 1997; 2001-2003; 2005; 2007; 2010 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 9)
  - Letters Written by Manuel Babbitt to Bill and Linda Babbitt, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 10)
  - Manny Babbitt Articles, 1998 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 11)
  - P. v. Babbitt, Media Coverage, 1999 February 22-March 16 (Video-tape 1)
  - Flashpoints, KPFA, Chuck Patterson and Ernie Spencer on Manny Babbitt - Side A; Flashpoints KPFA, Bill Babbitt and David Kaczynski - Side B, 1999 March 30-April 23 (Cassette 1)
  - Manny Babbitt Clemency Video, Media Version, Edited for Media Release, 1999 April 13 (Umatic 1)
  - Manny Babbitt Rally, 1999 April 25 (Video-tape 2)
  - In Re: Manny Babbitt Clemency Hearing, Witness: Walter Griffin, 1999 April 26 (Video-tape 3)
  - Declaration of William Babbitt, 1999 May (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 12)
  - Tribute to Manny Babbitt (unbound copy), 1999 July (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 13)
  - Tribute to Manny Babbitt (bound copy), 1999 July (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 14)
  - Clemency Video on Behalf of Manuel Babbitt, Edited for Media Release, 1999 (Video-tape 4)
  - Jesuit High School Clip; Good Morning America; NBC Evening News; Today Show, 1999 (Video-tape 5)
  - Manny Babbitt Articles (1 of 2), 1999 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 15)
  - Manny Babbitt Articles (2 of 2), 1999 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 16)
  - Letters to Governor Davis and Mayor Brown, 1999; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 17)
  - News Articles about Death Penalty, 1999-2001; 2005-2009 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 18)
  - Film Advocacy, 1999; 2001; 2005-2006 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 19)
  - Religious Views, 1999; 2004; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 20)
  - Manuel Babbitt Donation, 2000 March 13-15 (Video-tape 6)
  - Catherine Crier, Crier Today, "Innocent and Awaiting Execution," Illinois Moratorium on the Death Penalty, 2000 April 12 (Video-tape 7)
  - California Capitol Week, 2000 June 30 (Video-tape 8)
  - Manny Babbitt Loaves and Fishes Donations, 2000 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 21)
  - Manuel Babbitt Information Sheets, 2000; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 22)
  - Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation, 2000-2003; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 23)
  - Advocacy Newsletters, The New Abolitionists, 2000-2013 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 24)
  - Bill and Manny Babbitt Media Coverage, 2000-2013 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 25)
  - Bill Babbitt on WGN Radio's John Williams' Show, 2001 January 22 (Cassette 2)
  - Sally Jessy Raphael, "I Turned in a Family Member," with Bill Babbitt and David Kaczynski, 2001 February 26 (Video-tape 9)
  - And Then One Night: The Making of Dead Man Walking, 2001 September (Video-tape 10)
  - And Then One Night: The Making of Dead Man Walking, KQEDTV, 2001 October (Video-tape 11)
  - Advocacy in Finland, Caroline Koivisto, 2001-2002; 2004; 2007; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 26)
  - California Death Row Inmates, 2002 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 27)
  - Discrimination within Jury Selection Honors Thesis and Bill Babbitt Interview, 2002 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 28)
  - John Walsh Show with Bill Babbitt and David Kaczynski, 2003 February 19 (Video-tape 12)
  - Californians for a Moratorium on Executions, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 29)
  - Campaign for the Nobel Peace Prize for Governor Ryan of Illinois, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 30)
  - The History of California's Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 31)
  - Understanding Capital Punishment, 2003 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 32)
  - Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation, 2003-2008 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 33)
  - New York State Assembly Death Penalty Hearing, 2004 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 34)
  - A Question of Justice Character Clips, 2004 (Video-tape 13)
  - Unedited Character Clips, Question of Justice LLC, 2004 (Dvd 1)
  - NCADP Annual Conference, 2005 October 27-30 (Cd 1)
  - Anti-Death Penalty Poetry, 2005 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 35)
  - Capital Defense Handbook, 2005 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 36)
  - Murder Victims' Families for Human Rights (MVFHR), 2005-2007; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 37)
  - Conferences and Events, 2005-2008 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 38)
  - Advocacy Newsletters, Article 3, 2005-2012 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 39)
  - Death Penalty Forum, Buffalo, with Bill Babbitt and David Kaczynski, 2006 September 28 (Video-tape 14)
  - HourCNY WCNY-TV, 2006 October 2 (Dvd 2)
  - "Against Our Better Nature", 2006 (Dvd 3)
  - University at Albany Symposium, 2006 (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 40)
  - Communita di Sant'Egidio, Statements on the Death Penalty and in Support of the Campaign for a Moratorium, 2007 (Dvd 4)
  - Communita di Sant'Egidio, Supporting Documents, 2007 (Dvd 5)
  - Advocacy Magazines, 2007-2008; 2013; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 41)
  - Bill and Linda Babbitt Correspondence, 2007-2013; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 42)
  - Purple Heart Ceremony, James Davis, 2009 July 29 (Dvd 6)
  - Conferences and Events, 2009-2014; 2016; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 43)
  - An American Life, 2010 (Dvd 7)
  - Journey of Hope, 2010; 2013; Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 44)
  - Kenya Videos, Part 1, 2011 (Dvd 8)
  - Kenya Videos, Part 2, 2011 (Dvd 9)
  - Kenya Videos, Part 3, 2011 (Dvd 10)
  - Rwanda Pictures, 2011 (Dvd 11)
  - Rwanda Videos, 2011 (Dvd 12)
  - Uganda Pictures, 2011 (Dvd 13)
  - Uganda Videos, 2011 (Dvd 14)
  - Our America with Lisa Ling, "Families of Killers", 2013 (Dvd 15)
  - Advocacy Pamphlets and Backgrounders (1 of 2), Undated (Box 1 (3-Advocacy), Folder 45)
  - Advocacy Pamphlets and Backgrounders (2 of 2), Undated (Box 2 (3-Advocacy), Folder 1)
  - Babbitt Early History, Agawam River, Wareham, Oakdale, Undated (Cassette 3)
  - Babbitt, Karina, Grpn PA, Undated (Cassette 4)
  - Bill Babbitt Remarks, Undated (Box 2 (3-Advocacy), Folder 2)